《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash."
你不再是你自己了
You're no longer you.
你现在是负力的一部分
You're a part of a negative force.
斯旺的神速力是靠负面情绪推动的
Thawne's Speed Force is fueled by negative emotions.
-你做什么工作  -相信我
- What do you do? - Trust me,
如果我告诉你  你也不会相信的
you wouldn't believe me if I told you.
你没有超级满意自己的秘密身份
You're not super satisfied with your secret identity.
你是说我不想成为震波吗
Are you saying I don't want to be Vibe?
我们要是不处理掉那个匕首
There won't be any future for any metas
超能力者就不会有未来
if we don't get rid of that dagger.
如果有什么能够摧毁那把匕首的话
If anything's gonna destroy that dagger,
就是这支镜像枪
it's this Mirror Gun.
成功了
It works.
依循我的指示
Follow my instructions
我们就能打败蝉
and we'll defeat Cicada,
毁掉她的匕首
destroy her dagger,
然后救你的父亲
and save your father.
斯旺在操纵她
Thawne is manipulating her.
他被关在死囚牢房  他要怎样操纵她
He's on death row, how is he manipulating her?
这里边对不上
Something doesn't add up.
匕首就是斯旺的计划
The dagger is Thawne's plan.
别开枪
Don't shoot it!
我一直都想成为英雄
I always wanted to be a hero,
利用我非凡的能力来帮助别人
to use my extraordinary abilities to help people.
这就是我来这里的原因
That's why I came here.
为了见我的家人  为了阻止蝉
To meet my family, to stop Cicada,
想办法弥补闪电侠的事业
help fix the Flash's legacy,
避免他消失在未来中
and save him from disappearing in the future.
我坚信我有能力实现不可能的事
I believed I could do the impossible,
但我从未想过结果竟是如此
but I never imagined it would turn out like this.
不  不  他在做什么
No, no! What's he doing?
蝉  斯旺  匕首
Cicada--Thawne, dagger.
闪 电 侠
第五季
第二十二集
【本季终】
拉尔夫现在怎样
How's Ralph?
我从来没有见过这种情况
I've never seen anything like it.
我不能完全弄明白
I can't quite figure it out.
他的细胞反向运动
His cells are kinetically inverted.
似乎它们是自身的逆转
It's like they're the reverse of themselves.
应该多花时间弄明白
Should've spent more time trying to figure out
这个东西该如何运作
how this thing works.
我只是想不明白
I just don't understand
他为什么要跳到爆炸的面前
why he would jump in front of that blast.
为什么他要这样做
I mean, why would he do that?
这就是问题所在  不是吗
That's the question, isn't it?
这就是问题所在
That's the question.
另外  蝉二代依然下落不明
In other news, Cicada deuce is still MIA.
好吧  我们得去中城警局了
All right, we should get to CCPD,
看能不能找到对于追踪她有利的线索
see if we can find anything that could help us track her.
怎么了
What?
我待会应该和卡米拉约会的
I'm supposed to meet up with Kamilla later.
我还以为你们俩进展地很顺利
I thought things were going really well for you two.
的确
They are.
我只是还没告诉她
I just haven't told her about
我的另一个身份震波
my vibratory alter ego yet.
西斯科  如果你和她在一起是认真的
Cisco, if you're serious about being with her,
那么你应该告诉她真相
you have to tell her the truth.
我知道
I know.
所有没被治愈的超能力者
All the metas that we couldn't cure,
已经安全撤离
we got safely evacuated
他们在受保护的收容站里等候
and they're waiting at a protected holding facility.
做得好  你们两个都是
Nice work, both of you.
但是工作尚未完成
Well the work's not done yet.
我是说  超能力者只是暂时安全
I mean, the metas are safe for now,
但是蝉还逍遥法外
but Cicada's still out there,
所以人们仍处于危险之中
so the people are still in danger.
告诉我详细情况
Fill me in on the details.
我准备好迎接这场噩梦的终止
I'm ready for this nightmare to end.
这本应该早就结束
It should've been over already.
诺拉  听着
Nora, look,
我相信拉尔夫有合理的理由
I'm sure Ralph had a good reason.
在我们弄明白之前
Until we figure out what it is,
我们只要专注于这里就好  好吗
we just gotta concentrate on this, all right?
等一下
Wait a second.
这是什么
What is that?
看起来像木材
Looks like wood.
哪里来的
From what?
这里的地板是大理石
I mean the floor is marble,
家具没有被接触过
furniture's untouched,
天窗是由玻璃和金属制成的
and the skylight's made of glass and metal.
如果这不是来自蝉的进入口
Well if it didn't come from Cicada's point of entry...
她一定是从别的地方带进来的
She must've brought it from somewhere else.
我们现在该怎么做
What do we do now?
你知道该怎么做
You know what to do.
在他们最不经意的时候攻击
Hit them when they least expect it.
他们最不经意的时候
When they least expect it.
时间球
The Time Sphere.
一旦我修好它
If I repair it,
我就可以从粒子加速器爆炸的那晚
I can bring the last of the virus back
将剩下的病毒带回来
to the night of the Particle Accelerator.
当超能力者第一次出现在中城时
When meta-humans first appeared in Central City...
闪电侠成为英雄来阻止我
And the Flash becomes a hero to stop me.
在他们毁灭世界之前消灭超能力者
Destroy the meta-humans before they destroy the world.
他们都将难逃一死
They'll be born only to die.
肯定是某种木头碎片
Definitely some kind of wood fragment.
你觉得这些可以带我们找到蝉的藏匿点吗
And you think those will lead us to where Cicada's hiding?
我们可以查一下
We can find out.
我们可以对照检索它
We can cross-reference this,
看看这是什么材质的木头
see what kind of wood it is,
然后我们看结果如何
then see where we end up.
拉尔夫有好转吗
Is there any progress on Ralph?
没有  他仍处于昏迷状态
No, he's still unconscious,
我也想不出逆转他的细胞的方法
and I can't figure out a way to reverse his cells.
我估计这意味着  我们还不可以确定
So I guess that means we still don't know why
他跳到镜像枪面前的原因
he jumped in front of that Mirror Gun, do we?
我们可以
We do.
We do...
因为德比解决了最大的谜团
because Dibny solved the greatest mystery of all.
闪电侠的事业  怎样阻止蝉
The Flash legacy, how to stop Cicada,
为他的过去赎罪
repentance for his past sins--
艾尔伯德·斯旺帮助你的原因
all the reasons Eobard Thawne was helping you.
还有阻止爸爸在未来消失
And stopping Dad from disappearing in the future.
在未来消失也是一部分
Disappearing in the future is part of it, hmm?
但这和你父亲没有关系
But this has nothing to do with your father.
斯旺想打败蝉  摧毁匕首的
The real reason that Thawne wishes to defeat Cicada
真正原因
and destroy Cicada's dagger
是因为这匕首
is because this dagger
是唯一将逆闪电困在监狱的东西
is the only thing keeping the Reverse-Flash in prison.
看来是时候了
Guess this is it.
看起来是的  不是吗
Looks like it, doesn't it?
我差点忘了
I almost forgot.
我联系了闪电侠博物馆
I contacted the Flash Museum,
让他们今天送了样东西过来
had them send something over for today.
我想它应该和你一起
I thought it should be buried for good...
永远埋葬
along with you.
就当是送别礼物
Consider it a parting gift.
在过去摧毁蝉的匕首
Destroying Cicada's dagger in the past
会让斯旺免于在未来死去
will save Thawne from dying in the future?
没错
That's right.
蝉的匕首一直在抑制
Cicada's dagger has been dampening
斯旺的超能力
Thawne's powers all this time.
所以如果我们现在销毁匕首
So if we get rid of the dagger now,
它会在未来消失
it disappears in the future?
斯旺会逃离铁山监狱
And Thawne gets out of Iron Heights.
反向时间入侵
A reverse time hack.
你说的有关斯旺的一切都是对的
Everything you said about Thawne is true.
他唯一帮助的人就是他自己
The only person he ever helps is himself.
诺拉  这不是你的错
Nora, this is not your fault.
就是
Yes, it is.
现在我们要问的问题就是
Now the question we have to ask...
我们是阻止蝉还是阻止斯旺
do we stop Cicada or do we stop Thawne?
不  我们不能让上千超能力者死去
No, we're not gonna let thousands of meta-humans die,
不论现在还是未来
now or in the future.
我们找到蝉
We find Cicada.
彻底摧毁匕首
We destroy the dagger once and for all.
你得离开这里
You gotta get out of here.
不  我们得等结果
No, we gotta wait for the results--
你回来之前我们可以处理
We can handle it until you get back.
去找卡米拉吧
Go see Kamilla.
你怎么选
How do you choose?
这是要问爱瑞丝而不是我的问题
That's more of a question for Iris than for me.
她看起来对我的照片很满意
She seems to be happy with my photos.
我有点希望她可以让我去中城警局
I was kinda hoping she'd send me over to CCPD
拍超能力者
to take photos of the meta-humans
接受治疗的照片
when they were getting that cure.
你能想象蝉男袭击时你在那里吗
Can you imagine being there when that Cicada guy attacked?
实际上是蝉女
Cicada woman, actually.
女人
A woman?
她叫格蕾丝·吉本斯
Her name's Grace Gibbons.
她的叔叔是一代蝉
Her uncle was the first Cicada.
她在他接受了超能力解药后杀了他
She killed him after he took the meta-human cure.
我做的解药
The cure that I made.
你做的解药
The cure you made?
你是认真的
You're serious.
这就是你一直在做的科学项目
That's the scientific project you've been working on?
在尖端科研实验室
At S.T.A.R. Labs.
你从没告诉我你的实验室是尖端科研实验室
You never told me your lab was S.T.A.R. Labs.
还有很多我没告诉你
There's a lot I haven't told you.
这是什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
你是震波
You're Vibe.
听着  卡米拉
Look, Kamilla,
我亲眼看到双重身份的
I've seen firsthand how hard it is
生活有多难
to have two lives like this.
我不想拖累你
And I tried to separate you from that,
但是我不想再向你隐瞒了
but I don't want to keep this from you anymore.
我不能一直这样骗你
I can't keep lying to you like this.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
西斯科  等等
Cisco, wait.
我完全明白
I totally get it.
我读了很多漫画书
I've read a lot of comic books.
我知道关于透露秘密身份的
I know all the tropes that go with
所有梗
revealing secret identities.
但在现实生活中  我从来没有
But in real life, I would never expect you
期望你立刻告诉我这种事情
to tell me something like this right away.
你真好
You're amazing, you know that?
西斯科  这不关于我
Cisco, this isn't about me.
而是关于你
It's about you.
如果作为震波是你想要的生活
If being Vibe is a part of the life you want,
我绝不会阻拦
I would never get in the way of that.
你真的很像我
You know you really are a lot like me.
轻信
Trusting.
而且当事情变糟时你总是归咎于自己
And you always blame yourself when things go wrong.
我怎么弥补呢
How do I fix this?
我不知道你是否可以  诺拉
I don't know if you can, Nora.
你犯了一个错
You made a mistake,
你知道吗
you know?
一个大错
A big mistake.
有时候在生活中  我们能做的所有
Sometimes in life, all we can do is just
就是承受后果
live with the consequences.
所以你要问自己的问题就是
So what you have to ask yourself is
你想成为什么样的英雄
what kind of hero are you gonna be?
每犯一个错误就重新来过的人
One who takes a do-over after every mistake,
还是承担过错继续前进
or one who lives with it and moves forward?
没有进展
Nothing?
没有  我还是不知道怎么重置
Nope, I still cannot figure out how to reset
他的细胞到正常状态
his cells back to normal.
还是矮胖子的样子
He's till Humpty Dumpty'd, huh?
是的
Yep.
自从他第一次获得超能力
He hasn't been this much of a mess
他还没这么糟糕过
since he first got his powers.
自从...
Since...
那你们当初是怎么帮他的
And what did you do to help him then?
我们引入了一种稳定酶
We introduced a stabilizing enzyme that reset
用硫化还有肌肉记忆使他的身体
his body back to its original form using vulcanization...
恢复到原来的状态
and muscle memory.
肌肉记忆
Muscle memory.
那看起来现在我们需要做的
Well then it appears all that we need to do
就是叫醒他
is wake him up.
那你说我们要怎么做
How would you suggest we do that?
简单
Simple.
我们轰炸他
We blast him.
We blast him?
你轰炸他  用震动能量
If you blast him, the vibrational jolt,
完全足够重启他意志的了
it will be more than enough to kick-start his consciousness.
我可以肯定
I'm sure of it.
我们能不能就放点嘎嘎的歌
Can't we just play some Gaga
然后期望他能醒来
and hope he wakes up?
嘎嘎不能解决一切问题
Gaga is not the solution to everything.
我们必须轰炸他
You have to blast him.
上吧  小拉尔夫·马奇奥  请
Allez, young Ralph Macchio, please.
小心  这场面可能会失控
Be careful. This could get a little ugly.
好吧
Okay.
抱歉  兄弟
Sorry, deuce.
摔角大赛
WrestleMania!
看吧  和新的一样
Voilà! Good as new.
炸我为什么你发生了
Blasted why you happen what?
B-b-blasted why you happen what?
除了语言技巧
Except for the language skills.
会恢复的  大概
Those will return, probably.
你们去  都哪里
Everybody going, where is?
Everybody going where--every--
怎么了
What is it?
是你们找到的那个木头粒子
It's the wood particles you guys found.
瑞士灰
"瑞士灰"
"Swish ash."
欧洲本土开花白蜡树的一部分
Part of the flowering ash trees indigenous to Europe,
同时在我们这边有最大的一片丛林
but also make up our biggest wood space
离中城19公里远
not 12 miles from Central City.
科林斯森林
Kolins Woods.
蝉就是在那里差点杀了我
That's where Cicada almost killed me.
那里还是这个国家最大的
That's also one of the largest wooded parks
森林公园
in the country.
-我们需要个更好的计划  -我有一个
- We need a better plan. - I've got one...
可以同时阻止蝉和斯旺
that can stop Cicada and Thawne.
要找出
Out to sniff?
我们要用真的她塞西尔吗
So really we're using her Cecile?
她有高度敏感的共情能力
Well, she is a highly sensitive empath
蝉不断产出恨意
and Cicada emanates hate.
检察官塞西尔·霍尔顿将作为
DA Cecile Horton will serve
我们的早期预警装置
as our early warning detection system.
如果我们幸运  蝉会措手不及
If we're lucky, Cicada won't see what's coming.
然后一旦我们找到并困住蝉
Then once we find Cicada to entrap her,
我们给年轻的格蕾丝用解药的选择
we give Young Grace the choice to take the cure.
希望在她不再是超能力者之后
And hopefully, when she's no longer a meta...
那个贱人就不会存在了
That bitch will cease to exist.
这样我们就可以在不摧毁匕首的情况下
That way we can stop her without destroying
阻止她  然后斯旺也不会逃脱
the dagger and Thawne never goes free.
现在你要做的就是帮助格蕾丝
Now all you have to do is help Grace
做下正确的选择
make the right choice.
我要怎么说
What do I say?
发自内心的话  她会听的
Whatever's in your heart. She'll listen.
真是堆多愁善感的废话
What a bunch of sentimental crap.
你俩听起来就像是安伯电影里的人物
You two sound like a friggin' Hallmark movie.
我懂你  姐妹
I hear ya, sister.
我想我们接近了
I think we're close.
你还好吗
You good?
是  天啊  抱歉
Oh, yeah, jeez, sorry.
这边走
Uh, this way.
来吧
Here we go.
球体准备好了
The Sphere is ready.
我们可以离开了
We can leave.
各位  我们找到她了  准备好
Guys, we found her. Get ready.
我其实挺高兴你在我们离开前找来了
I'm actually glad you found me before we left.
现在我可以杀你两次了
Now I can end your lives twice today.
有我在就别想
Not on my watch.
-困住她了  -诺拉  该你了
- We got her. - Nora, you're up.
如果你能和成人的格蕾丝相连接
If you can connect to Grace as an adult,
你也可以和童年的她连接
you can connect with her as a child.
你只需要进入她的愤怒之中
You just have to tap into her anger.
你可以做到的
You can do this.
你不该回来这里的  诺拉
You shouldn't have come back here, Nora.
我必须回来  格蕾丝
I had to, Grace,
因为有很多人会死  除非你帮助我
because a lot of people are gonna die unless you help me.
如果我能帮忙  你会是第一个死的
If I can help it, you'll be the first to die.
能量力场的完整度
Uh, the force field's integrity
刚降低到百分之86了
just went down to 86%.
格蕾丝  我知道你认为
Grace, I know you think
你叔叔想要所有超能力者死
your uncle wanted all metas dead,
但他也是个超能力者
but he was a meta.
所以他才使用了解药
That's why he took the cure
而且他也想要你使用
and why he wants you to have it too.
你是个超能力者  和你叔叔一样
You're a meta, just like your uncle.
不我不是  收回你的话
No I'm not! Take it back.
百分之70  52
70%... 52...
别听她的  格蕾丝
Don't listen to her, Gracie.
这仇恨  正在吞噬你的
This hate. It's consuming you,
把你变成怪物
turning you into a monster.
更糟的是  你会孤身一人
And what's worse, you're all alone.
奥林叔叔不会离开我的
Uncle Orlin wouldn't leave me.
他没有选择
He had no choice.
和你叔叔一样使用解药吧
Take the cure just like your uncle did.
不
No.
百分之40
40%.
诺拉得马上说服格蕾丝
Nora's gotta convince Grace now.
超能力者杀了你的父母  格蕾丝
Metas killed your parents, Gracie.
他们都要死
They all deserve to die.
别相信他  格蕾丝
Don't believe him, Grace.
这不过是你的思想作祟
This is just in your mind.
她是对的  格蕾丝
She's right, Gracie.
所以你才创造了他
It's why you created him.
他是那个照顾你的人
He's the man who took care of you.
百分之19
19%.
我知道有一部分的你知道这是错的
I know a part of you knows that this is wrong.
但是你邪恶的另一半正在外面
But the other dark part of you is out there
在现实世界里滥杀无辜
in the real world killing innocent people.
你可以选择去阻止这一切
You can make a choice to stop it.
怎么阻止
How?
醒来并注射解药
Wake up and take the cure.
闭嘴
Shut up.
你能做到的  格雷西
You can do this, Gracie.
准备好
Get ready.
障碍力场
力场强度
格蕾丝
Grace.
-格雷西  -格蕾丝
- Gracie. - Grace.
-格雷西  醒醒  -格雷西  醒醒
- Grace. Grace - Grace. Grace.
-格雷西
- Grace!
好吧  我不希望有人死
Okay, I don't want people to die.
我会注射解药
I'll take the cure.
谢谢
Thank you.
她去了
Here she comes.
准备好了么
Okay.
起作用了吗  大伙  发生什么了
Did it work? Guys, what's happening?
乔  不要
Joe, no!
现在我来斩草除根
Now I'll finish what I started.
没起作用
It didn't work.
她头里的碎片
That shard in her head.
它仍然是那个匕首的一部分
It's still part of the dagger.
它的暗物质足够抵消解药
Its dark energy is enough to counteract the cure.
要想治好格蕾丝  我们必须摧毁匕首
If we want to cure Grace, we must destroy that dagger.
你夺走了我的家人  闪电侠
You took my family away from me, Flash.
现在看我夺走你的
Now watch me take yours.
不要
No!
巴里
Barry!
时间刚好
Just in time.
先生们
Gentlemen.
很遗憾的通知你们
I hate to inform you, but...
你们都死了
you're all dead.
斯旺
Thawne...
我  我能帮助你
I--I can help you.
这不是很讽刺吗
Isn't this ironic?
是时候悔改了
Time to repent.
就把这当做临别礼物吧
Consider this a parting gift.
时间  刚
Just...in...
可以啊
Well, well.
看来某些人搞明白了如何逆转时间
It appears as if someone has figured out how to reverse time.
聪明的女孩
Clever girl.
我们全都搞清楚了
We figured out everything.
真的吗
Oh, really?
你都搞清楚什么了
What have you figured out?
我们搞清楚了你为什么把诺拉送到过去
We figured out why you sent Nora back,
你为什么让她打下迪沃的卫星
why you had her punch DeVoe's satellite--
为的是创造一个我们可以阻止的蝉
to create a Cicada we could stop.
是吧
Right?
一个我们能摧毁的匕首
A dagger we could destroy.
就是这个匕首一直监禁着你  对不对
It was the dagger that was keeping you in prison all along, wasn't it?
是的
That's right.
15年了
15 years.
这是第二次我非自愿地被监禁15年
The second time I've been stuck somewhere against my will for 15 years.
太无聊了
Boring.
当然  除了你的到访
Except for your visits, of course.
你忽略了最令人愉快的部分
You're leaving out the most delightful part:
你们俩如何帮助我逃脱的
how you both helped me escape.
我们帮的你
We helped you?
没错  当你进入时间穹顶  还记得吗
That's right. When you traveled to the Time Vault, remember that?
我们需要帮手来搞明白怎样将暗能量
Oh, we need help trying to figure out how to drain dark energy
从那个"逃脱追捕的家伙"身上提取出来
from the "One who got away."
蝉
Cicada!
有印象吗  在时间穹顶里
Remember that? When you blurted that out
你脱口而出  所以几年之后
in the middle of the Time Vault, so that years later,
当蝉的匕首被绑在我胸前的时候
when I ended up with Cicada's dagger strapped to my chest,
我清楚的知道我该做什么
I knew exactly what I had to do:
让诺拉·艾伦相信我  太简单了
get Nora Allen to trust me. Easy.
就像当初让你相信我一样
Just like when I got you to trust me,
之后所有的事情都迎刃而解
and then everything starts falling into place.
为什么
Why?
因为我是唯一一个知道
Because I am the only speedster
如何去操纵时间线
that knows how to manipulate the timeline
以达到我的目的的极速者
to get what I want,
我精心编排着我需要的每一个变化
orchestrate the changes that I need,
其中一部分
some of which...
正在发生
are happening right now,
为的是保证一件事
to ensure one thing:
就是我能脱离束缚
that I go free.
我们不需要匕首来监禁你
We don't need a dagger to stop you.
那么
Well then,
让我看看你爸爸都教你什么了
let's just see how much your father taught you.
看来你这个老师做的不如我
I guess you're not as good a teacher as I am.
你救不了他的  诺拉
You can't save him, Nora.
无论你做什么
No matter what you do,
无论你尝试什么  闪电侠都会消失
no matter what you try, the Flash will always vanish.
那是他的宿命
That is his legacy.
这可真好
Is this nice?
闪电侠小队  又在一起了
Team Flash, back together again...
还有个新人
with a new guy.
拉尔夫·迪比
Ralph Dibny.
欢迎啊  你本应该死了的
Welcome. You should be dead.
是啊  我想咱俩这点很相似
Yeah, I guess we have that in common.
这个问题我们等下就能解决
We'll take care of that in a moment.
爱瑞丝  总是很高兴见到你
Iris. Always a pleasure.
冰霜杀手
Frost.
西斯科
Cisco.
再次见到你心里暖暖的
It warms my heart to see you again.
我想道个歉
I want to apologize for--
但是我不那么做
But had I not done that,
你永远没办法变得如此非凡
you never would've had the means to become extraordinary.
我不需要超能力就能做到非凡
I don't need powers for that.
就是现在
Now!
消失不是我爸的宿命  斯旺
It's not my father's legacy that's gonna disappear, Thawne.
该消失的是你的
It's yours.
诺拉
Nora!
如此接近了  小极速者
So close, Little Runner.
反正你也永远不会成功
It was never going to work anyway.
妈妈  爸爸
Mom? Dad?
-不  不  -妈妈  发生什么了
- No, no, no, no. - Mom, what's happening?
-一个新的时间线开始了  -什么
- A new timeline is setting in. - What?
你毁掉匕首时创造了一个新的时间线
A new timeline that you created when you destroyed the dagger!
我很抱歉  小极速者
I'm sorry, Little Runner,
像这样利用了你
for trading you in like this.
但是我得确保我能获得自由
But I had to be sure that I could go free.
你还有机会救她  巴里
You can still save her, Barry.
还有时间  你还可以救她
There's still time. You can still save her.
怎么救
How?
负神速力
The Negative Speed Force.
她必须得去那
She has to go there.
那里是唯一免疫时间线改变的地方
It's the only place immune to timeline changes.
但你现在就得走了
But you have to go now.
你得走了  巴里
You have to go, Barry!
不然我们就要永远失去她了
Or we lose her forever.
没错  我也挺喜欢她的
That's right. I've grown fond of her too.
在很多方面
In many ways.
她让我知道到有女儿是什么样的体验
She's shown me what it's like to have a daughter.
我们下场危机再见
See you in our next crisis.
我做不到
I can't do this.
你能行的  你必须这么做  好吗
Yes you can, yes you can. You have to, all right?
只要再坚持一会儿就行
Just hold on a little longer.
不  爸爸  我做不到
No, Dad, I can't.
诺拉
Nora!
我做不到
I can't.
-诺拉  这是做什么  -太晚了
- Nora, what are we doing? - It's too late.
不  还没有  我们得回去
No, it's not. We gotta go back.
-爸爸  不是的  -巴里  你得把她带回去
- Dad, no. - Barry, you have to take her back.
我明白  我明白
I know, I know.
-妈妈  妈妈  -我明白  我明白
- Mom, Mom. - I know, I know.
诺拉  你现在得回去了
Nora, you have to go back now.
不要
No!
如果我进了那里  负神速力就会
If I go back in, the Negative Speed Force
永远成为我的一部分
will be a part of me forever.
不  我们会把它从你体内驱散的  诺拉
No, we'll get it out of you, Nora.
我们能把它消除  能救你的  求你  我保证
We can get it out. We can save you. Please, I promise.
妈妈  你没办法的
Mom, you can't.
你们都不行
None of you can.
它会让我变得像斯旺一样
It's making me like Thawne.
充斥着愤怒和仇恨
Full of anger and hate.
我不想这成为我的宿命
I--I don't want that to be my legacy.
-这都是我造成的  -不是的
- This is all on me. - No.
全部都是
All of it.
我的错
My mistake.
我不想一错再错了
And I'm not gonna make another one.
有时你能做的只有自食其果
Sometimes all you can do is live with the consequences.
我的天啊
Oh my god.
没事的  没事的
It's okay. It's okay.
会没事的
It's okay.
我们爱你
We love you.
谢谢你们为我做的一切
Thank you for everything.
我们都非常遗憾
We are so sorry.
我们得相信会有机会再见到她的
We have to believe that we'll see her again.
我们会的
We will.
诺拉
Nora...
是她让我们在今晚没有失去一切
made sure that we didn't lose everything tonight.
她拯救了城里的每个超能力者
She saved every meta in the city.
她也给了格雷丝一个全新的未来
And she gave Grace a new future.
给了我们所有人新未来  对吗
Gave all of us, right?
尤其是我
Especially me.
如果没有诺拉  我就不会遇到一生所爱  瑞内
Without Nora, I never would've met the love of my life, Renee.
你也不会成功阻止你的第三十八个蝉
And you wouldn't have stopped your 38th Cicada.
或是你的第三十九个
Or your 39th.
没错
Right.
这是段不可思议的旅程
It's been quite a journey.
很高兴遇见你
Pleasure.
我很荣幸  闪电侠
An honor, Flash.
如果没有你  我们不可能解开这个谜题
We never could've solved this mystery without you.
话别说太满
Well, don't be too sure.
你们之中已经有一位大师级的侦探了
You already have a master detective in your midst.
恭喜  成年长颈鹿
Congratulations, Adult Giraffe.
做得好  歇洛克
Well done, Sherloque.
夏洛克
Sherlock.
行了  废话少说
Well, all right then. Without further ado.
我的朋友们
Mes amis.
祝你们好运  闪电小队
Good luck, Team Flash.
是辛格
It's Singh.
是的  他想让我们去中城警局见他
Yeah, he, uh--he wants us to meet him in CCPD
还说要把巴里带去
and bring Barry.
好的  去吧
Yeah, go.
正好我也有点想一个人静静
I kinda want to be alone anyway.
你没事吧
Is everything okay?
斯旺所说的
What Thawne said...
不是我想要的
I don't want that.
我不想自己人生的唯一亮点
I don't want the extraordinary thing about my life
只是我的超能力
to be my powers.
没人这么想
No one feels that way.
事情是这样的
Here's the thing.
我会这么想
I do.
这么多年来  我都想着
All these years I thought that
震波是我该成为的那个人
Vibe was the person I was supposed to be.
我想现在轮到该做回西斯科的时候了
I think it's time Cisco finally got his turn.
所以那是什么意思
So what does that mean?
意思就是我要使用解药
It means I want to take the cure.
-如果你这么做  -就没有回头路了
- If you do this... - There's no going back.
我知道
I know.
我和冰霜杀手都会很想念震波的
Killer Frost and I are really gonna miss Vibe.
我也是
Me too.
你感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
害怕
Scared.
但我心怀希望
But I'm hopeful.
趁我还没忘记
Before I forget,
我在工作室给你留了点东西
I left you something in the workshop.
就是  我用来表达谢意的
Just, you know, my way of saying thank you.
谢什么
For what?
谢谢你做我的好朋友
Being a great friend.
中城警局
格蕾丝·吉本斯目前已经安排
Well, Grace Gibbons is currently scheduled
和指派律师见面了
to meet with our county counselor.
我们会尽快让她进入
And as soon as possible, we'll get her in
一个好的寄养家庭
with a good foster family.
是这样  我不会耽误太久
Look, I won't keep you long,
但我只是想谢谢你们
but I just want to thank you
在与蝉的对抗中冲在前线
for being at the forefront with Cicada.
只是本职工作  长官
Just doing our job, sir.
你们做的远远不止本职工作那么简单
Well, you went way beyond just doing your job.
我知道你们的付出
And I know you did it because of
是因为你们很关心这座城的市民
how much you care for the people of this city,
这让我可以很放心地把它交给你们
which is how I know I can leave it in your capable hands.
什么叫交给
What do you mean, leave it?
市长给我提供了一份工作
The mayor's offered me the job
作为新的警察局长
as the new chief of police.
什么
What?
-戴夫  -大卫
- Dave. - David.
-恭喜你  -真好
- Congratulations. - That's great.
谢谢你们
Thank you, thanks.
当然这也意味着我要去寻找替代者
Of course that leaves me responsible for finding my own replacement.
我想
And, uh...
我希望是你  乔
I would like that to be you, Joe.
替代你
Re--replace you?
作为队长
As--as captain?
乔·韦斯特队长
Captain Joe West.
我喜欢这个称呼
Oh, I like the sound of that.
而且不用担心
And don't worry.
如果这边的事情变得不可控
If things get dicey, as they tend to around here,
会有很多人帮助你的
you'll have plenty of help.
对不对  闪电侠
Isn't that right, Flash?
别装了  巴里
Oh come on, Barry.
我也是个警探
I'm a detective too.
长官
Sir.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
我一定尽我所能
I'll do my best.
我现在明白我爸爸的意思了
Now I know what my dad meant
他当初说做家长就好像
when he said being a parent is like wearing your heart
把你的心暴露在身体外面
on the outside of your body.
是的
Yeah.
斯旺跑掉了
Thawne got away.
又一次
Again.
诺拉也走了
Nora's gone.
本应感到是一种失去  可是
Should feel like a loss but,
我还感到了
I also feel...
-骄傲  -骄傲  是的
- Pride? - Pride, yeah.
她很棒
She did good.
是的
Yeah.
她是我们最好的结合
She was the best of both of us.
她一直是我的最好的继承者
She was my legacy all along.
我们的  一起的  作为一个家庭
And us, together, as a family,
我想被这样记住
that's how I want to be remembered.
作为一个好人
As a good man,
一个有爱的丈夫
a loving husband...
一个支持的父亲
A supportive father.
你已经是全部这些了
You're already all of those things.
诺拉也是这么想的
Nora felt that way too.
时间语言
Time language.
无论时间线怎样改变
No matter what changes with the timeline,
它永远不会变
that'll never change.
我们可以一直用这个想起她
We'll always have this to remember her.
爸爸妈妈
Hi, Mom and Dad.
如果你们在看这段画面
If you're watching this,
意味着出现了一些意外
it means that something went wrong.
但我不想让你们难过
But I don't want you guys to be sad.
我不难过
I'm not.
我一直梦想当个英雄
I always wanted to be a hero,
用我非凡的能力去帮助别人
to use my extraordinary abilities to help people.
所以我来到了这里
That's why I came here:
来见我的家人  阻止蝉
to meet my family, stop Cicada,
帮忙修补闪电侠的事业
help fix the Flash's legacy,
挽救他  不让他在未来消失
and save him from disappearing in the future.
我以为我能完成这些难题
I believed I could do the impossible,
但我从没想到事情会发展成这样
but I never imagined it would turn out like this.
我庆幸是这样
I'm glad it did.
我没有改变任何
I wouldn't change anything
和你们相处的时间
about my time with you,
我亲爱的父母
my sweet parents,
世上对我最重要的人
the most important people to me in the world.
我真希望我可以在那边  庆祝每个新篇章
I wish I could be there to celebrate every new chapter,
见证每次成功
to witness every success.
要知道
Just know...
无论我这一生去哪里
that no matter where I go in my life,
你们总会陪着我
you'll always be my side.
因为你们
Because of you,
我知道我永远不会真正的孤单
I know I will never, ever, truly be alone,
我会感受你们的爱与支持  像温暖的拥抱
and I will feel your love and support like a warm hug
抚慰着我
comforting me,
督促我成为最好的自己
pushing me to be the best person I can be.
迪
尔
本
感谢你们所做的一切
Thank you for everything...
让我成为了英雄
For making me a hero.
即使我不完美还依然爱我
For loving me even if I wasn't perfect.
请一定要记住我爱你们
Please remember that I love you both.
直到永远
And I always will.
无论未来发生什么
No matter what the future breaks.
收到时间短片
Incoming time flicks.
闪电侠消失于危机中